Sam Avery

sam.avery1@gmail.com | (617) 852-9701 linkedin.com/in/samanthajavery

Summary

Skilled operations and program manager who recently completed Flatiron's Fullstack Software Engineering bootcamp. Possesses skills in program management, software development, and building documentation that helps teams of any size drive projects forward. With time spent at YouTube and at Studio, comfortable in any environment from large corporation to small startup. Experience combines technical, operational, and soft skills.

Professional Experience

Studio | January 2022 – August 2022

Operations Associate

- Program managed the lifecycle of new class content and curriculum, implementing new classes on the consumer-facing Studio website using VS Code and ensuring cross-functional teams were aligned on deliverables throughout the process.
- Executed class launches, company rebranding, and new product initiatives with multiple engineering teams, the curriculum team, the marketing team, and the post-production team.
- Managed a freelance Quality Assurance associate. Conducted the hiring process, created software walkthrough documentation, used technical judgment for bug triage, and escalated issues to Engineering as needed.

YouTube | May 2016 – July 2021

Operations Specialist | April 2019 – July 2021

- Program managed the e-learning tool used across YouTube Spaces globally, maintaining content and user processes.
- Managed a global group of 20+ subject matter experts to identify work problems and goals for Google's event, e-learning, and finance tools.
- Led bi-weekly bug review and quarterly prioritization of feature requests and bugs, working with engineers to resolve tickets and improve user experiences for users at all YouTube Spaces. Conducted UAT for engineers as necessary.
- Developed documentation for user roadmaps, tools training, FAQs, SOPs, onboarding, and institutional knowledge.

Events Specialist (Data Analyst) | May 2016 - April 2019

- Executed multiple processes and workflows for approx. 10 15 events per month at YouTube Space LA.
- Trained team on internal tools and processes, product updates, and security procedures to protect attendee data.
- Analyzed data, maintained data integrity, led data clean-up initiatives, and leveraged analytic insights to improve events.

Technical Projects

WeAte. | A dinner party planner.

• Used Ruby on Rails and React to create an app that helps users plan dinner parties. App | GitHub | Demo

Tutoring Appointments | A resource to help track and create tutoring appointments.

• Used React and Ruby to create a tutoring resource, allowing users to create, view, and delete sessions. GitHub | Demo

Volunteer Experience

The Heart Series | February 2015 – February 2020

Program Manager

- Orchestrated the volunteer program for this social impact conference, spearheaded communications, training sessions, and placements for 30+ volunteers.
- Supervised multiple workflows and check-in stations for 200+ attendees, speakers, and press.
- Project managed on-site operations of volunteers and vendors.

Education

Boston University

Masters of Science, Media Ventures | August 2015 Bachelor of the Arts, Psychology | January 2014

Skills

React • Ruby on Rails • JavaScript • CSS • SQL • Figma • Program Management • Operations • Training and Documentation • Customer Success • QA • UAT • VS Code • Notion • Salesforce • Asana • Smartsheets • Drip • GitHub • Google Workspace